<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: interface-tech | Random thoughts | Hari KT]]></title>
  <link href="http://harikt.github.com/blog/categories/interface-tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harikt.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T23:33:41+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://harikt.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Hari K T]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 and Upcoming Web Technologies]]></title>
    <link href="http://harikt.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/node-218/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T19:41:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://harikt.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/node-218</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Probably you may have already heard about the full day workshop on HTML5 and Upcoming Web Technologies by <a href="https://twitter.com/shwetank">Shwetank Dixit</a> of Opera at <a href="http://interface-tech.in/">Interface</a> which will be held on 3rd November 2012 . Where ? The Woods Manor, Cochin . Why you should participate? HTML5 is the future of internet. Why not learn from the leader? Who should attend ? Are you a web developer? A person who works on android, iphone or any device ? If you said yes, then its for you. What is the cost? This time we are charging 500 INR. The money is used to give you tea/coffee and snacks plus an awesome lunch during the event and to cover the event expenses. I don't think its a huge amount for I have been spending more than 500 INR to travel from Cochin to Bangalore to participate in such awesome workshops. You are only spending a 500 INR in a year which will be a worth in your career. There is also discounts available for group registration for companies, please contact Sofie Holmberg via sofie.holmberg at interface-tech dot in or 0484 4433638 . There is only limited seats available , so be there and don't loose the best chance attending the workshop and interacting with <a href="https://twitter.com/shwetank">Shwetank Dixit</a>. Register and get your tickets from : http://interface-tech.in/register</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
